# Rafi Hassan Chowdhury



+880 1701459732



Mirbag, Moghbazar, Dhaka



linkedin.com/in/rafi-hassan-b9b63a1a6



rafihassan@iut-dhaka.edu



github.com/Grumpy-Frog



Portfolio: grumpy-frog.github.io/rufi.github.io/

#### **About Me**

I am a fresh graduate who enjoys collaborating with teams in a positive manner. With prior experience working with diverse teams, I possess a strong enthusiasm for Software Development, Data Science and Machine Learning. I also enjoy participating in competitions such as Hackathons, Datathons, Machine Learning Olympiads.

#### **Education**

# Islamic University of Technology

B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA: 3.66 out of 4.00

2020 - June, 2024

## **Experience**

## **Battery Low Interactive**

• Position: Game Development Intern.

Baridhara J Block, Dhaka May 2023 - July 2023

#### MetaFour Asia Ltd.

• Position: Junior Software Engineer (Java).

1 Sonargaon Janapath, Dhaka August 2024 - Present

#### Skills

Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, Python, Assembly, R
Libraries/Frameworks: Django, OpenCV, OpenGL, JavaFX

Tools/Platforms: GitHub, Jira, Linux
Databases: SQL, MySQL, SQLite
Game Engine: Unity, Unreal Engine
System Software: Android Studio

# **Honors & Awards**

- Champion of IUT ICT Fest 2024 Datathon: ASR for Regional Dialects powered by Bengali Ai. (Team Leader)
- 2. Best Notebook Winner of IUT ICT Fest 2024 Dataton: ASR for Regional Dialects powered by Bengali Ai. (Solo)
- 3. Champion of ML OLYMPIAD BANGLADESH 2024 by Tensorflow. (Team Leader)
- 4. Champion of WEB-OFF by IUT Computer Society, 2023. (Team Leader)
- 5. Finalist in National Blockchain Olympiad Bangladesh 2023. (Team Leader)
- 6. Award of Recognition in International Blockchain Olympiad 2023. (Team Leader)
- 7. Finalist(Kaggle Public 1st) in "UIU Bhashamul: Bengali Regional IPA Transcription", 2024 powered by Bengali Ai. (Team Leader)
- 8. Finalist Yobo Al Hackathon 2024. (Team Leader)
- 9. Programming Contest- 7th in Intra IUT Coderush 1.0, 2023.
- 10. Capture The Flag-8th in Intra IUT Coderush 1.0, 2023.

## **Co-Curricular Activities**

- 1. C++ and Python instructor for pre-level students.
- 2. Machine Learning instructor
- 3. IUT Computer Society member
- 4. Volunteer at IUPC ICT Fest 2024

#### Untitled Survival Game GitHub Link Itch.io Link

- · Language: C++, GLSL
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Developer
- Framework/Technologies: OpenGL, OpenAL, Blender, MagicaVoxel
- **Description:** A 3D Horror puzzle game with timed maze solving. Randomized mazes with maze generation algorithm, grass enemies, and Al bots using A\* pathfinding.

## Untitled Tank Game GitHub Link

- · Language: C++
- · Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Developer
- Framework/Technologies: SFML, Adobe Photoshop, GIMP
- **Description:** A 2D shooter game with PvP and co-op modes. Players level up, fight AI, and grab power-ups like speed boosts. Handcrafted animations and unique assets for a fresh experience.

### Anda Lorai FPS Game GitHub Link Itch.io Link

- · Language: C#
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Developer
- Framework/Technologies: Unity, Blender, Photon Network Engine
- **Description:** A 3D FPS multiplayer shooter game where players control eggs, engaging in battles to score points within a set time; Photon Engine (PUN) is utilized for networking.

# Virtual Classroom GitHub Link

- · Language: Python, JavaScript, C++
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Full Stack Developer
- Framework/Technologies: Django, SQLite, Agora RTC, OAuth
- **Description:** An educational website connecting teachers and students, featuring Google Authentication, classroom creation, assignments, MCQ exam grading, video meetings with screen sharing, and knowledge-sharing articles. Users manage profiles and passwords.

# Untitled-Music-Player GitHub Link

- Language: Java
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Developer
- Framework/Technologies: JavaFX, MySQL
- Description: A feature-rich Music Player with database storage, playback speed adjustment, and metadata-based sorting. Unique features include a Frequency Spectrum Visualizer, URL playback, and customizable themes using CSS files.

## <u>Doodlelt: Image to Doodle</u> <u>GitHub Link</u>

- · Language: Python
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Project Researcher
- Framework/Technologies: Generative Adversarial Network/ PyTorch
- **Description:** A machine learning project that employs a Pix2Pix Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) to create doodles based on an input image.

# IUTCS Website GitHub Link Website Link

- Language: Python, JavaScript
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Project Initiator, Full Stack Developer
- Framework/Technologies: Django, PostgreSQL
- **Description:** A website for IUTCS, where they can host intra/inter-university events, facilitate participant registration, and showcase organization updates, blogs, and achievements.

# IUTRS Website GitHub Link

- Language: Python, JavaScript
- Responsibilities: Team Leader, Full Stack Developer
- Framework/Technologies: Django, PostgreSQL
- Description: This website was made for IUT Robotics Society